Railway Labor Executives' Association Additional Records 5728
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
- Series XI: Office Files, 1981
  - Railway Labor Executives Association: Railroad Labor/Management Relations, 1981 (Box 48, Folder 6)
  - Railway Labor Executives Association: Immigration Problems, 1981 (Box 48, Folder 7)
    Correspondence in re issues of seniority districts with Canadian railroaders.
  - Railway Labor Executives Association: Subcommittee on Alcoholism and Drug Abuse, 1981 (Box 48, Folder 8)
  - Railway Labor Executives Association: Train-the-Trainer Manual for the Employee Assistance Program Workshop, 1981 (Box 48, Folder 9)
  - Railway Labor Executives Association: Committee on Railroad Retirement, 1981 (Box 48, Folder 10)
  - Railway Labor Executives Association: Committee on Railway Labor Act, 1981 (Box 48, Folder 11)
  - Railway Labor Executives Association: Committee on National Transportation Policy Mergers, Consolidations, and Passenger Service, 1981 (Box 48, Folder 12)
  - Railway Labor Executives Association: Legislative Representatives, 1981 (Box 48, Folder 13)
  - Railway Labor Executives Association: Director Governmental Affairs Legislative Report, 1981 (Box 48, Folder 14)
  - Railway Labor Executives Association: Passes, 1981 (Box 48, Folder 15)
  - Railway Labor Executives Association: Prospective Employees (General), 1981 (Box 48, Folder 16)
  - Railway Labor Executives Association: Financial Statements, 1981 (Box 48, Folder 17)
  - Railway Labor Executives Association: Lawyers (General), 1981 (Box 48, Folder 18)
  - Railway Labor Executives Association: Lawyers Bills [folder 1 of 3], 1981 (Box 48, Folder 19a)
  - Railway Labor Executives Association: Lawyers Bills [folder 2 of 3], 1981 (Box 48, Folder 19b)
  - Railway Labor Executives Association: Lawyers Bills [folder 3 of 3], 1981 (Box 48, Folder 19c)
  - Railway Labor Executives Association: Strikes (General), 1981 (Box 48, Folder 20)
  - Railway Labor Executives Association: Press Releases, 1981 (Box 48, Folder 21)
  - Railway Labor Executives Association: Rail Labor Rally, April 29, 1981. (Box 48, Folder 22)
    Planning documents for rally.
  - Railroads: General, 1981 (Box 48, Folder 23)
  - Railroads: Railroad Ownership, 1981 (Box 48, Folder 24)
  - Railroads: Auto Train Corporation, 1981 (Box 48, Folder 25)
  - Railroads: Association of American Railroads, 1981 (Box 48, Folder 26)
  - Railroads: National Railway Labor Conference (NRLC), 1981 (Box 48, Folder 27)
  - Railroads: Hospital Associations (General), 1981 (Box 48, Folder 28)
  - Other Organizations: American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations (AFL-CIO), 1981 (Box 48, Folder 29)
  - Other Organizations: Committee on Political Education, 1981 (Box 48, Folder 30)
  - Other Organizations: Legislative Council, 1981 (Box 48, Folder 31)
  - Other Organizations: Executive Council, 1981 (Box 48, Folder 32)
  - Other Organizations: Miscellaneous and General, 1981 (Box 48, Folder 33)
  - Other Organizations: National Safety Council, 1981 (Box 48, Folder 34)
  - Other Organizations: Transportation Research Forum, 1981 (Box 48, Folder 35)
  - Other Organizations: National Association of Retired and Veteran Railway Employees, 1981 (Box 48, Folder 36)
  - Other Organizations: Labor Bureau of the Middle West (Gus Homer), 1981 (Box 48, Folder 37)
    Includes ICC filings in re Docket No. 37025
  - Other Organizations: LABOR Newspaper, 1981 (Box 48, Folder 38)
    Includes financial reports, annual report, and minutes of meeting of Board of Directors.
  - Other Organizations: Special Election Year Editions of LABOR Newspaper, 1981 (Box 48, Folder 39)
  - Other Organizations: National Association of Railroad Passengers (NARP), 1981 (Box 48, Folder 40)
  - International Affairs: General, 1981 (Box 48, Folder 41)
  - International Affairs: Bureau of International Labor Affairs (Foreign Visitors), 1981 (Box 48, Folder 42)
  - Commuter Problems: General, 1981 (Box 48, Folder 43)
    Includes telegraph from member organizations asking RLEA to use its lawyers to file a temporary injunction against SEPTA.
  - Railway Labor Executives Association: Brotherhood of Maintenance of Way Employees, 1981 (Box 48, Folder 44)
  - Railway Labor Executives Association: Brotherhood of Railway and Airline Clerks, 1981 (Box 48, Folder 45)
    Includes BRAC newsletters
  - Railway Labor Executives Association: Hotel and Restaurant Employees, 1981 (Box 48, Folder 46)
    Includes card announcing change of name of the organization.
  - Railway Labor Executives Association: Seafarers International Union, 1981 (Box 48, Folder 47)
  - Railway Labor Executives Association: Transport Workers Union, 1981 (Box 48, Folder 48)
  - Railway Labor Executives Association: United Transportation Union, 1981 (Box 48, Folder 49)
  - Railway Labor Executives Association: International Longshoremen's Association, 1981 (Box 48, Folder 50)
  - Railway Labor Executives Association: Meetings (General), 1981 (Box 48, Folder 51)
  - Railway Labor Executives Association: Miami Meeting, 1981 (Box 48, Folder 52)
    Minutes of meeting and correspondence.
  - Railway Labor Executives Association: Agendas, 1981 (Box 48, Folder 53)
- Series XII: Desk Files, 1981
  - Desk File, January-February 1981 [folder 1 of 2] (Box 49, Folder 1a)
  - Desk File, March 1981 (Box 49, Folder 2)
  - Desk File, April-June 1981 [folder 1 of 2] (Box 49, Folder 3a)
  - Desk File, April-June 1981 [folder 2 of 2] (Box 49, Folder 3b)
- Series XIV: Office Files, 1984
  - Government: Executive Branch, 1982 (Box 49, Folder 4)
    Includes Executive Orders establishing three Emergency Boards. Also includes a letter from the RLEA respectfully requesting the removal of a candidate being considered for the ICC because she has no experience in the field and the announcement of her appointment by Reagan.
  - Government: House and Senate, 1982 (Box 49, Folder 5)
    Newsletter from Rep. Clarence D. Long, "The Reagan Unemployed Need Help Now!"
  - Government: Agencies (General), 1982 (Box 49, Folder 6)
  - Government: United States Environmental Protection Agency, 1982 (Box 49, Folder 7)
  - Government: Department of Transportation - Staff Appointments, 1982 (Box 49, Folder 8)
  - Government: Transportation Association of America - Harriman Awards, 1982 (Box 49, Folder 9)
  - Government: Department of Transportation, 1982 (Box 49, Folder 10)
    Newsletters and circulars
  - Government: National Transportation Safety Board Railroad Accident Report - Rear-End Collision of Louisville and Nashville Railroad Company Trains, December 28, 1981., 1982 (Box 49, Folder 11)
  - Government: National Transportation Safety Board Railroad Accident Report - Side Collision and Derailment of Norfolk and Western Railway Company Trains, November 28, 1981., 1982 (Box 49, Folder 12)
  - Government: National Transportation Safety Board Railroad Accident Report - Derailment of Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Authority Train 410, January 13, 1982. (Box 49, Folder 13)
  - Government: National Transportation Safety Board Railroad Accident Reports, 1981 - Brief Format, 1982 (Box 49, Folder 14)
  - Government: National Transportation Safety Board Railroad Accident Report - Head-On Collision of AMTRAK Trains Extra 769 East and Number 195, March 29, 1982. (Box 49, Folder 15)
  - Government: National Transportation Safety Board - Annual Report to Congress, 1981, 1982 (Box 49, Folder 16)
  - Government: National Transportation Safety Board Railroad/Highway Accident Report - Miller Transporters, Incorporated Tractor Cargo Tank-Semitrailer/Southern Railway Freight Train Collision and Fire, September 15, 1981., 1982 (Box 49, Folder 17)
  - Government: National Transportation Safety Board Railroad Accident Report - Rear-End Collision of New York City Transit Authority Subway Trains 142NL and 132NL, July 3, 1981., 1982 (Box 49, Folder 18)
  - Government: National Transportation Safety Board Railroad Accident Report - Head-On Collision of Boston and Maine Corporation Extra 1731 East and Massachusetts Bay Transportation Authority Train Number 570, August 11, 1981., 1982 (Box 49, Folder 19)
  - Government: National Transportation Safety Board Special Investigation Report - Eight Subway Train Fires on New York City Transit Authority with Evacuation of Passengers, 1982 (Box 49, Folder 20)
  - Government: National Transportation Safety Board Special Investigation Report - Derailments of New York City Transit Authority Trains Involving Traction Motor Mount Failures, 1982 (Box 49, Folder 21)
  - Government: National Transportation Safety Board Railroad Accident Report - Head-On Collision of AMTRAK Trains Extra 769 East and Number 195, March 29, 1982. (Box 49, Folder 22)
  - Government: National Transportation Safety Board (General), 1982 (Box 49, Folder 23a)
    Circulars, press releases, and safety recommendations.
  - Government: National Transportation Safety Board, Accident Investigation - Report No. 82-1: Bessemer and Laker Erie Railroad Company; Report No. 82-2: Louisville and Nashville Railroad Company, 1982 (Box 49, Folder 23b)
  - Government: National Transportation Safety Board - Analysis of Locomotive Cabs.", 1982 (Box 49, Folder 23c)
  - Government: Federal Railroad Administration - Staff Appointments, 1982 (Box 49, Folder 24)
  - Government: Federal Railroad Administration, 1982 (Box 49, Folder 25)
    Includes testimony from RLEA to the House and Senate subcommittees on the Department of Transportation in re appropriations.
  - Government: Office of Railroad Safety - Safety Inspectors, 1982 (Box 49, Folder 26)
  - Government: Department of Transportation-Federal Railroad Administration Safety - Rules, Regulations, Petitions, 1982 (Box 49, Folder 27)
  - Government: Safety Appliance Acts, 1982 (Box 49, Folder 28)
  - Government: Highway Grade Crossing Matters, 1982 (Box 49, Folder 29)
  - Government: Power Brakes, 1982 (Box 49, Folder 30)
  - Government: Locomotive Inspection, 1982 (Box 49, Folder 31)
  - Government: Signal Rules, Standards, and Instructions (RS and I Cases), 1982 (Box 49, Folder 32)
  - Government: Approval of Changes in Signal Installations (BS-AP Cases), 1982 (Box 49, Folder 33)
  - Government: Hours of Service, 1982 (Box 49, Folder 34)
  - Government: Track Maintenance and Inspection Standards, 1982 (Box 49, Folder 35)
  - Government: Accident Reports and Governing Regulations, 1982 (Box 49, Folder 36)
  - Government: Occupational Safety and Health Administration (OSHA), 1982 (Box 49, Folder 37)
  - Government: Labor Department (General), 1982 (Box 49, Folder 38)
  - Government: Urban Mass Transportation Administration Section 13(c) - General [folder 1 of 3], 1982 (Box 49, Folder 39a)
  - Government: Urban Mass Transportation Administration Section 13(c) - General [folder 2 of 3], 1982 (Box 49, Folder 39b)
  - Government: Regional Transportation Authority - Proposed Five-Year Transit Program Fiscal Years 1983-1987, 1982 (Box 49, Folder 40)
  - Government: Interstate Commerce Commission - Rail Services Planning Office, 1982 (Box 49, Folder 41)
    Includes newsletters and statistical data om Class I railroad employees.
  - Government: Interstate Commerce Commission - Membership and Staff Appointments, 1982 (Box 49, Folder 42)
  - Government: Rules of Practice and Administrative Procedure, 1982 (Box 49, Folder 43)
  - Government: ICC Statistics (M-350), 1982 (Box 49, Folder 44)
  - Government: Ex Parte Sub 1 - Special Procedures for Proposed Railroad Abandonment, 1982 (Box 49, Folder 45)
  - Government: Ex Parte 274 Sub 8 - Proposed Rule Making, 1982 (Box 49, Folder 46)
  - Government: National Mediation Board (General), 1982 (Box 50, Folder 1)
    Includes correspondence in re the closing of NRAB physical offices by the General Service Administration. Also includes correspondence in re other consequences of the Reagan administration's budget.
  - Government: Emergency Board Reports, 1982 (Box 50, Folder 2a)
    Report of Emergency Board 194
  - Government: National Mediation Board - Membership and Staff Appointments, 1982 (Box 50, Folder 2b)
  - Government: National Mediation Board - Rules of Procedure and Administration, 1982 (Box 50, Folder 3)
  - Government: Special Board of Adjustment 605, Regarding February 7, 1965 Agreement - Awards, 1982 (Box 50, Folder 4)
  - Government: Arbitration Board 298, 1982 (Box 50, Folder 5)
  - Government: National Railroad Adjustment Board (General), 1982 (Box 50, Folder 6)
    Includes Fact Sheet by RLEA about the purpose of the NRAB and the adverse effects the closing of it, because of a lack of funds in Reagan's budget, would have.
  - Government: National Railroad Adjustment Board - First Division, 1982 (Box 50, Folder 7)
  - Government: National Railroad Adjustment Board - Second Division, 1982 (Box 50, Folder 8)
  - Government: National Railroad Adjustment Board - Third Division, 1982 (Box 50, Folder 9)
  - Government: National Railroad Adjustment Board - Fourth Division, 1982 (Box 50, Folder 10)
  - Government: National Railroad Adjustment Board - Organizations Qualified to Participate in the Selection of Members, 1982 (Box 50, Folder 11)
  - Government: National Railroad Adjustment Board - Membership, 1982 (Box 50, Folder 12)
  - Government: Railroad Retirement Board (General) [Folder 1 of 2], 1982 (Box 50, Folder 13a)
    Correspondence in re the financial situation of the retirement fund and proposed legislation, lists of railroad job vacancies, a statement by Reagan proposing privatizing the Railroad Retirement System, letters announcing the reduction of personnel working on the Railroad Retirement Board, and a transcript of congressional budget hearings for FY 1983.
  - Government: Railroad Retirement Board (General) [Folder 2 of 2], 1982 (Box 50, Folder 13b)
  - Government: Reports for Railway Labor Executives Association Meetings from the Railroad Retirement Board, 1982 (Box 50, Folder 14)
  - Government: Railroad Retirement Board - Membership and Staff Appointments, 1982 (Box 50, Folder 15)
  - Government: Railroad Retirement Board - Administrative Practices and Procedures, 1982 (Box 50, Folder 16)
  - Government: Railroad Retirement Board - Field Offices - Schedule of Regular Itinerant Service, 1982 (Box 50, Folder 17)
  - Government: Railroad Retirement Board - Status of Funds, Actuarial Reports - Monthly Benefit Statistics, 1982 (Box 50, Folder 18)
  - Government: Railroad Retirement, Benefits, Unemployment Insurance Systems [folder 1 of 2], 1982 (Box 50, Folder 19a)
    Newsletters and circulars.
  - Government: Railroad Retirement, Benefits, Unemployment Insurance Systems [folder 2 of 2], 1982 (Box 50, Folder 19b)
  - Government: Railroad Retirement Board - Fifteenth Actuarial Valuation of the Assets and Liabilities under the Railroad Retirement Acts, 1982 (Box 50, Folder 20)
    Covers up to December 31, 1980. Bound.
  - Government: Railroad Retirement Board - Annual Report Statistical Supplement of 1980, 1982 (Box 50, Folder 21)
  - Government: Railroad Retirement Board - Fifteenth Actuarial Valuation of the Assets and Liabilities Under the Railroad Retirement Acts with Technical Supplement, 1982 (Box 50, Folder 22)
  - Government: Railroad Retirement Board - Fifteenth Actuarial Valuation of the Assets and Liabilities Under the Railroad Retirement Acts with Technical Supplement, 1982 (Box 50, Folder 23)
  - Government: Railroad Retirement Board - Educational Programs, Meetings, Films, Etcetera - Scheduled Informational Conferences, 1982 (Box 50, Folder 24)
  - Government: Railroad Retirement Board - Supplemental Retirement Plans, 1982 (Box 50, Folder 25)
  - Government: Railroad Retirement Board - National Reporting Officers Memoranda, 1982 (Box 50, Folder 26)
  - Government: Railroad Retirement Board - Administration of Medicare, 1982 (Box 50, Folder 27)
  - Government: President's Committee on the Handicapped, 1982 (Box 50, Folder 28)
  - Government: President's Committee on the Handicapped - Membership Directory, 1982 (Box 50, Folder 29)
  - Government: National Railroad Passenger Corporation (AMTRAK), 1982 (Box 50, Folder 30)
    RLEA Fact Sheets in support of Amtrak, for using during budget negotiations.
  - Government: United States Railway Association, (Created by the Regional Rail Reorganization Act (3R Act)), 1982 (Box 50, Folder 31)
    Photocopied packet of newspaper clippings from march 12-16, 1982.
  - Government: Railway Labor Executives Association Labor Subcommittee 880 (James E. Burke, Chairman), 1982 (Box 50, Folder 32)
    Includes Awards of SBA No. 880, notices of meeting of subcommittee, reports on Conrail employees, and reports on old Title V claims.
  - Government: Consolidated Rail Corporation (CONRAIL), 1982 (Box 50, Folder 33)
    Includes correspondence in re the NERSA Fact Finding panel.
  - Railway Labor Executives Association: Purchase of CONRAIL (Brian M. Freeman), 1982 (Box 50, Folder 34)
    Includes correspondence from RLEA to Conrail employees keeping them appraised of the situation, proposals for an employee stock option plan (ESOP), a report by the RLEA task force on the sale of Conrail, photocopies of newspaper clippings, and correspondence with financial institutions in re financing an ESOP.
  - Government: United States Railway Association - CONRAIL Performance Review, 1981 (Box 50, Folder 35)
  - Government: Department of Energy (General), 1982 (Box 50, Folder 36)
  - Judicial: Court Cases (General), 1982 (Box 50, Folder 37)
  - Railway Labor Executives Association: General, 1982 (Box 50, Folder 38)
    Includes correspondence in re the State of Texas's Rail Safety Study. Also includes newspaper clipping in re the merger of Burlington Northern and the Southern Railway.
  - Railway Labor Executives Association: Constitutions and By-Laws, 1982 (Box 50, Folder 39)
  - Railway Labor Executives Association: Officers and Members, 1982 (Box 50, Folder 40)
  - Railway Labor Executives Association: American Railway and Airway Supervisors Association, 1982 (Box 50, Folder 41)
  - Railway Labor Executives Association: American Train Dispatchers Association, 1982 (Box 50, Folder 42)
  - Railway Labor Executives Association: Brotherhood of Railroad Signalmen, 1982 (Box 50, Folder 43)
  - Railway Labor Executives Association: Brotherhood of Railway Carmen of the United States and Canada, 1982 (Box 50, Folder 44)
  - Railway Labor Executives Association: International Brotherhood of Boilermakers and Blacksmiths, 1982 (Box 50, Folder 45)
  - Railway Labor Executives Association: International Association of Machinists and Aerospace Workers, 1982 (Box 50, Folder 46)
  - Railway Labor Executives Association: International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers, 1982 (Box 50, Folder 47)
  - Railway Labor Executives Association: International Brotherhood of Firemen and Oilers, 1982 (Box 50, Folder 48)
  - Railway Labor Executives Association: International Organization of Masters, Mates, and Pilots of America, 1982 (Box 50, Folder 49)
  - Railway Labor Executives Association: National Marine Engineers Beneficial Association - Joint Maritime Congress, 1982 (Box 50, Folder 50)
  - Railway Labor Executives Association: Railroad Yardmasters of America, 1982 (Box 50, Folder 51)
  - Railway Labor Executives Association: Sheet Metal Workers International Association, 1982 (Box 50, Folder 52)
  - Railway Labor Executives Association: Brotherhood of Locomotive Engineers, 1982 (Box 50, Folder 53)
  - Railway Labor Executives Association: Brotherhood of Maintenance of Way Employees, 1982 (Box 50, Folder 54)
  - Railway Labor Executives Association: Brotherhood of Railway, Airline, and Steamship Clerks, 1982 (Box 50, Folder 55)
  - Railway Labor Executives Association: Hotel Employees and Restaurant Employees International Union, 1982 (Box 50, Folder 56)
  - Railway Labor Executives Association: Seafarers International Union, 1982 (Box 50, Folder 57)
  - Railway Labor Executives Association: Transport Workers Union, 1982 (Box 50, Folder 58)
    Includes broadside announcing upcoming political fights to protect the Railroad Retirement Board and pensions.
  - Railway Labor Executives Association: United Transportation Union, 1982 (Box 50, Folder 59)
  - Railway Labor Executives Association: International Longshoremen's Association, 1982 (Box 50, Folder 60)
  - Railway Labor Executives Association: Meetings (General), 1982 (Box 50, Folder 61)
  - Railway Labor Executives Association: Miami Meetings, 1982 (Box 50, Folder 62)
    Correspondence and minutes to meeting.
  - Railway Labor Executives Association: Agendas, 1982 (Box 50, Folder 63)
  - Railway Labor Executives Association: Legal Cases (Agenda Item 2.1), File 1 [folder 1 of 3], 1982 (Box 51, Folder 1a)
    Includes a report from counsel on all cases being handled for RLEA. Also includes filings in various bankruptcy proceedings, appeal briefs, their case against SEPTA, against Conrail, and against the U.S.
  - Railway Labor Executives Association: Legal Cases (Agenda Item 2.1), File 1 [folder 2 of 3], 1982 (Box 51, Folder 1b)
  - Railway Labor Executives Association: Legal Cases (Agenda Item 2.1), File 1 [folder 3 of 3], 1982 (Box 51, Folder 1c)
  - Railway Labor Executives Association: Legal Cases (Agenda Item 2.1), File 2 [folder 1 of 3], 1982 (Box 51, Folder 2a)
    Includes a second report from counsel on all cases being handled for RLEA. Also includes filings in various bankruptcy proceedings, appeal briefs, their case against SEPTA, against Conrail, and against the U.S.
  - Railway Labor Executives Association: Legal Cases (Agenda Item 2.1), File 2 [folder 2 of 3], 1982 (Box 51, Folder 2b)
  - Railway Labor Executives Association: Legal Cases (Agenda Item 2.1), File 2 [folder 3 of 3], 1982 (Box 51, Folder 2c)
  - Railway Labor Executives Association: Railway Labor Executives Association versus Southeastern Pennsylvania Transportation Authority, Consolidated Rail Corporation, and AMTRAK Commuter Services Corporation, 1982 (Box 51, Folder 3)
    Bound. July 12, 1982.
  - Railway Labor Executives Association: Patrick W. Simmons and Railway Labor Executives Association versus Interstate Commerce Commission and United States of America and State of Michigan, Department of Transportation, et al., 1982 (Box 51, Folder 4)
    Bound. April 7, 1982.
  - Railway Labor Executives Association: Patrick W. Simmons and Railway Labor Executives Association versus Interstate Commerce Commission and Untied States of America and State of Michigan, Department of Transportation, et a;., 1982 (Box 51, Folder 5)
    January 26, 1982. Bound.
  - Railway Labor Executives Association: Railway Labor Executives Association vs. William M. Gibbons et al., 1982 (Box 51, Folder 6)
    March 30, 1982. Bound.
  - Railway Labor Executives Association: Assessments, 1982 (Box 51, Folder 7)
  - Railway Labor Executives Association: Applications for Affiliation, 1982 (Box 51, Folder 8)
  - Railway Labor Executives Association: Milwaukee Railroad Reorganization, 1982 (Box 51, Folder 9)
  - Railway Labor Executives Association: New York, Susquehanna, and Western Reorganization, 1982 (Box 51, Folder 10)
  - Railway Labor Executives Association: Chicago, Rock Island, and Pacific Railroad Company Reorganization, 1982 (Box 51, Folder 11)
  - Railway Labor Executives Association: Health and Welfare, 1982 (Box 51, Folder 12)
  - Railway Labor Executives Association: Travelers Insurance Company/Employee Certification, 1982 (Box 51, Folder 13)
    Includes bound insurance plan guide.
  - Railway Labor Executives Association: Travelers Dental Plan, Group Policy GA-874710, 1982 (Box 51, Folder 14)
  - Railway Labor Executives Association: Washington Job Protection Agreement Cases [folder 1 of 3], 1982 (Box 51, Folder 15a)
    Filings before the Section 13 committee.